# **Nick Bolles**

https://www.NickBolles.com | https://Portfolio.NickBolles.com www.LinkedIn.com/in/NickBolles | www.Github.com/NickBolles

10210 Rustling Birch Rd. Apt 221 Verona, WI 53593 (715) 781-5549 me@NickBolles.com

## **About Me**

Hey! I'm Nick! I love development, business philosophy, and discovering new technologies. I have experience with a wide range of technologies, with a passion for web development and emerging technologies. I take an iterative, agile approach to development and emphasize clean code, unit testing, CI/CD, open source and standards-based technology. I also have a business focused mindset; I enjoy brainstorming ways to solve business challenges with technology solutions to achieve efficient, effective, and low cost results.

I spend much of my free time doing hobby development, focusing on the javascript ecosystem and learning new technology. I have developed a few apps, mostly for learning purposes and they are available on my Gitlab server/Portfolio page. Check my website for more info and links to my LinkedIn, Github and the Gitlab server that I run., and my portfolio for an overview of some of the things I've worked on.

## Some of my Skills

- Strong understanding of business and how technology can influence day-to-day business operations
- Strong knowledge of the software development process and how aspects affect business outcomes
- Excellent development skills including: Typescript/ESNext, Angular (1.x and 2+), React, Vue, SASS/CSS, NodeJS, Nest.js, MongoDB, GraphQL, .Net, REST, Design patterns, Database design, and more
- Extensive experience with software development tools and methods such as Git, SVN, Docker, Jest, Github/Gitlab, Gitlab CI/CD, Jira, NPM, Webpack, Gulp, Cordova, Balsamiq, Agile, Scrum etc.

# **Experience**

#### Epic, Verona WI - Software Developer

June 2017 - Present

- Full stack developer (MUMPS, ASP.Net, Typescript) involved in 3 large projects, 25+ enhancements and 150+ fixes, responsible for requirement analysis, technical and UI design, dev and coordinating testing and documentation
- Continuously learn about healthcare, including on site observation, and solve complex healthcare challenges
- Recruiting partner, including mentoring new team members, conducting phone screens and grading coding exercises
- Application point person for several areas, such as performance testing and training tools
- Assisted in establishing two new areas of ownership for complex and company-wide integrated functionalities
- Designed and developed batch edit tool to save thousands of hours a year across the healthcare industry
  - Work with Epic's custom ASP .Net framework to elegantly display progress and results in bulk with great UX
  - Developed generically to enable 5+ projects, within a year, to utilize it to reduce dev time and improve features
- Advocate for team and entire company developer experience including usage of Typescript, Decorators, better IDE support, advanced CSS, JSX and React as well as internal tools such as Typescript to MUMPS and Record Global.

#### **Epic, Verona WI** - Software Developer Intern

May 2016 - August 2016

- Designed and developed a mobile IOS app in Swift and presented prototype to peers and division leaders
- Effectively communicated with end users and mentors to incorporate feedback into design

#### Geodigital, Mendota Heights, MN - Software Developer Intern

May 2014 - January 2016

- Worked with Delphi, SQL, JQuery, Kendo UI and .Net to implement dynamic documentation webapp for web services as well as implement numerous features in the InfoCenter web app.
- Only summer intern to secure a position beyond the scheduled internship end date of August 2014

## Education

#### **University of Wisconsin - Whitewater -** *Double Major*

September 2013 - May 2017

- Bachelor of Business Administration in Information Technology Emphasis on Business Analysis
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science